If it works, we call it ML. If it
doesn't work, we call it AI. Security is
a real concern. AI is a very kind of
volatile world on it. Are you seeing
security truly blocking organizations
and enterprises from embracing AI into
the systems? I would say well over 80%
of our customers are embracing AI within
the organization. If you ask me the
second question, what is the biggest
concern? It is security, but I would say
it's more of a concern than a blocker.
And in fact, adoption rates are
extremely high, especially in the
development community. The security
people you talk to, they wish AI wasn't
adopted. Or are they also excited? The
developers I talked to all want to use
it. In fact, if the organization doesn't
allow it, I would say chances are better
than 50% for sure that they're using a
windsurf or a kodium or a cursor
co-pilot or something within their
environment. So, they're definitely
excited and energized by it.
[Music]
Uh Danny, uh thanks a lot for sort of
coming in. I know we uh we kind of
barged in on a on a day of recordings. I
think you've had a whole bunch of them
today on it. So we'll uh we'll test you
out live here on it. That works. I don't
usually wear a sport coat, but uh you
know, just just for you today, I wore a
sport coat. Yeah, you're doing sort of
wearing the the formal wear is like I
guess if anybody knows anything about me
is like definitely sort of in the in the
uh uh sneaks original culture uh not so
much a suit sort of environment on it
but uh I think as we sort of barge into
like protect enterprise customers on it.
It's like a little bit of a showy or
serious lens to it that uh that was
great. Um so let me kind of uh just
introduce you a little bit. You know
people have kind of heard too much about
me uh on it but just talk a little bit
uh Danny about your background. Uh
Danny's uh I've had the pleasure of
knowing Danny. Oh wow. I'm sort of uh I
think a little bit embarrassed that I
was like I think it's not quite 20 years
but it's sort of starting to kind of
push that envelope on it. Uh uh as we
were building together some of the
original ABSSE products back in Sanctum
Watchfire uh and uh always uh sort of
was always at the cutting edge of sort
of understanding where we're building
out. Ended up uh continuing to lead some
uh uh research and security research at
IBM after it acquired uh Watchfire which
we worked at together. Um and then
through a bunch of sort of startup
journeys uh uh before sneak was CTO at
VH software talking also about sort of a
different type of risk right sort of
managing uh backup software uh in big
volume in the world of cloud which was
uh not always embracing we'll touch on
that a little bit security as as a first
principle uh on it and then uh lastly
you know we got the uh the chance to uh
draw you in to uh to Sneak to to come
and be sneak CTO on it which is very
exciting. So like a long uh amazing
history that I've had the pleasure of
sort of uh uh working with you in some
parts of it uh in the world of of risk
of security of it uh and today sort of
dive in a lot into AI. Um so uh did I
get any of that uh sort of wrong over
there uh Daniel on it? Any key pieces
you want to add? No, that's 100% it hit.
I always like to remind people I started
as a pen tester actually doing security
testing but I don't do very much of that
anymore. it uh it's been a fun journey
and and actually working with you along
alongside you over the years has made it
even better. So great to be here.
Um so uh I guess we're going to go from
uh kind of go through a little bit but
maybe the unpleasant topic of uh hey you
can just sort of a vibe code your way
and sort of have and not carry some
consequences. We're going to try not to
be sort of too much sort of doom and
gloom, you know, because I think we're
both believers uh in it. Um and and
maybe maybe just to before we cap in, I
know you've been sort of delving into uh
AI today. You're sort of with the
security hat, but also developer hat in
uh in Sneak. Uh do you want to say just
a couple of words about the type of AI
uh work uh that's been happening that
you've been immersed in before we get
into the subject matter?
Well, I always start the conversation
when people ask me about AI of what is
AI because I remember doing uh you know
cracking hash codes 20 years ago by
chaining up a whole bunch of FPGAAS and
so machine learning and and we've
evolved into where we are today. So I
usually like to start with that AI for
myself at least when I when I use the
term AI I tend to think of generative AI
which is more relatively newer in
nature. Um, but as you might expect,
we've been playing with all kinds of
generative AI here on the the sneak
side. Certainly, the one that comes up
the most is generating code, as I expect
most of the audience here is using some
kind of generative AI in the code world.
Yeah. Yeah. Very much so. I uh I
recently heard uh just like a bit of a
snarky but still kind of true uh remark,
which is uh if it works, we call it ML.
If it doesn't work, we call it AI. which
was uh which was kind of a little bit
funny like it's been around for a while.
Uh some stuff the new frontier. Um so I
guess uh we're going to cover a little
bit the security concerns of it and I
guess maybe just to tee that up as as a
question. So security is uh is a real
concern. AI is a very kind of volatile
world on it. uh and generally the the
the sense I get in conversations is that
often times security is a bit of a
blocker or at least a very kind of
source of anxiety uh when people are
embracing AI. So I guess my question to
you for starters is like what are you
seeing? Are you seeing security sort of
uh truly blocking organizations and
enterprises from embracing um uh AI into
the systems? uh is it you know are they
adopting it anyway or is it actually
slowing down? What are you seeing? Uh
we're definitely seeing them adopt it.
What I would say is unequivocally uh
people are moving forward with AI. If
you ask me kind of in the enterprise is
the customers of sneak it tends to be
you know certainly coding assistance we
see a lot of that but you also see a lot
of chat bots you see a lot of support
technologies and uh I would say well
over 80% of our customers are embracing
AI within the organization. Now if you
ask me the second question of what is
the biggest concern as they're doing
that it is security but I would say it's
not blocking things it's more of a
concern than a blocker in the adoption.
In fact adoption rates are extremely
high especially in the development
community. Yeah. And I'm curious like
are you feeling are the security people
you talk to, you know, they wish AI
wasn't adopted or are they also excited
to sort of have AI adopted? They're just
also afraid of the repercussions.
No, no, they're excited by it. The
developers I talked to all want to use
it. In fact, if the organization doesn't
allow it, I would say chances are better
than 50% for sure that they're using a
Windsor or, you know, a Kodium or a
cursor or a co-pilot or something within
their environment. So they're definitely
excited and and uh energized by it. The
one thing I would say is sometimes they
because this comment is now everyone's a
developer. Sometimes I think well really
like just because you know how to talk
to a prompt does that make you a
developer? So there is you know there
there's some cynicism there but they're
all adopting it. They're embracing it is
what I would right. Yeah. And I think um
I guess one thing I've uh I've been
excited to sort of see is that actually
probably like many people within the
security organizations are uh are like
highly technical but not good coders. Uh
and in that sense I see many of them
actually of embracing small tools uh the
creation of small tools with AI uh for
their own systems. Not like the way they
would identify attackers but just sort
of integration software or automation
software of it. um which I think is kind
of fun sort of to bring if you if you
think hearken back to the cloud if I use
that analogy you know in cloud um uh I
think there was probably more aversion
or my sense was there was more aversion
about the security team they kind of
preferred to not use it and and here
sort of feels like they're they're a
little bit of a user uh as well uh or an
embracer I don't know if you're sort of
seeing that in the world of app techch
uh as well
yeah I'd say that's definitely the case
and and one of the areas is they're
using it for curiosity I unfortunately
began my career I guess back in cobalt
and so if you ask me what I'm most
familiar with it's languages that are
older today or considered older C and
C++ and cobalt and and those but and and
Python because I did a lot of security
testing but for example I will freely
admit I'm not very good at at Golang and
so one of the ways I wanted to do
something in Go so you know I broke out
a coding assistant and I said hey can
you create this and so what I'm seeing
in the development community is they're
using it to both augment skills in areas
that they may not have skills. Um but
they're using it to satiate the
curiosity of how do I use this in my
everyday life. Yeah. Cool. So I guess um
um when when people are u assessing a
security concern again I'm going to
probably like overdo the cloud analogy
over here in this conversation but uh um
you know when when the cloud came about
and it had a bunch of sort of security
uh uh concerns around it the the
solution was sometimes expected to come
from the cloud itself you know from the
platform itself and over time I guess we
sort of seen uh platforms like Snake
platforms like for sort of cloud native
development or or like whiz or sort of
others for sort of CSPM and such
actually be the solutions that layer on
top of the cloud. So instead of it being
built in I guess how many do do you do
you have a sense of how do people feel
about uh hey the models will just become
secure or like know these these sort of
code generations they will kind of fix
it on their own versus a need for sort
of dedicated security solutions sort of
above above the fold.
Well, absc people definitely believe
that it's not going to secure itself and
developers generally are more optimistic
and think that it will secure itself and
I I think that both are true. The
analogy to the beginning of of cloud
is actually super relevant because
if you think about the when the cloud
first started taking off I mean it was
booming because people were saying hey I
can get our I can get footprint in an
area that I don't have and if you fast
forward after the inception of cloud two
or three years three big things were
result of that one is uh we're still
dealing with the security
misconfigurations of storage right open
S3 buckets like no one is doing anything
about that then there was over
permissive AM and and access controls.
And thirdly, there was very poor
visibility and logging. And I would say
that those same three concepts apply
equally to AI. It's very much the same.
And and security people who are aware of
this and know this say this is the era
that we're entering into. We're setting
ourselves up for failure if we don't
consider security going forward. Right.
Yeah. And they can anticipate that. And
of course, some of the question is well,
what can you do about it? Um and I think
I guess another uh topic we've had in uh
when when we think indeed about sort of
cloud and about application security is
this notion of like transcending
fragmentation right of uh if you're
using one model it might maybe have the
aspiration that it will sort of secure
itself you know all those concerns but
when you're using kind of multiple
models you know do you do you kind of
expect each of them to just sort of
secure itself or do you need something
that's overarching I guess when you're
looking at enterprises today are you are
you seeing them generally like you pick
a partner and kind of go all in with
them or you sort of see a breadth of
tool and and kind of model adoption
definitely a breadth of model and tool
adoption even I I'll use our
organization as an example we have
multiple coding assistants that are
being used here and we're using
multimodal things and we use you know
open AI for one thing we use claude 37
for another thing and and so that is
what I would say is typical and so if
you want governance across all the
different tools across all the different
models, then you need something that is
outside of those environments.
And while some models are better than
others at securing things, I would say
there are zero models that can secure
everything. And so having some awareness
of the types of weaknesses, I think is a
pretty important thing for most
organizations to focus. So that's an
excellent tea precisely to my next
question, which is let's sort of get a
little bit more sort of technical. So
like what are the security concerns that
people raise uh the most as you as you
sort of engage with them and especially
when it comes sort of AI development
right and uh in this world sort of
saying a little bit about the OS top 10
and the OS by 11 top 10 sort of the
developer audience doesn't necessarily
uh not everybody know what those are.
Sure. Yeah. So, the Open Web Application
Security Project has always had a top 10
of of vulnerabilities. And uh in 2023,
which two years ago is a lifetime ago,
but it was two years ago, they published
a top 10 vulnerability list for LLMs. Um
the first one of those was Prompt
Injection, and it went on from there to
model poisoning and data theft and data
exfiltration. And you can you can Google
it and find what those top 10 are. I
would say even in the two years since
that came to pass, I would say those
vulnerabilities tend to be out of date
because we're already facing new
vulnerabilities. When you have an agent
talking to an agent, there is no concept
of the vulnerabilities associated with
that. Um, so it's evolving and it's
evolving very quickly. So much so that
the standards bodies and and
organizations like OAS are it's it's
hard to keep up with those
vulnerabilities. Some of them though I
would argue guy are more real than
others. In other words, I think some are
overhyped but but some are more real and
they'll have jevity too. So let's dig
into that. Maybe like you know a couple
of examples of like which ones do you
think maybe we'll start with the uh the
uh the real ones and then we'll sort of
talk a little bit about the ones blown
out of proportion. So like which
concerns do you find um maybe like if if
you named your own sort of top three uh
that someone we have an audience here of
developers are sort of building software
like which top three concerns them or
their organization should really kind of
uh focus on?
There are two that I personally worry
about a lot in the long term. One is
around identity and access management.
And the reason I say that is because
typically LLMs the large language models
are trained with all kinds of data. And
it's not true that everyone inside the
organization should have access to all
kind all of that data. And so you hear
this being used as jailbreaking the
system or getting data that you're not
supposed to have access to. That is
exacerbated tenfold when you have agents
talking to agents which we're beginning
to see now where you have some agent
using model context protocol to speak to
another agent and there's no concept of
passing on authorization. Obviously
authentication has been done but
authorization the second model. So I
worry about that a lot in the concept of
code. Let me give you a specific example
of this. If if you have an LLM that has
all of your internal code libraries, you
may have code libraries for one group
that you don't want exposed to another
group. Well, how do you ensure that your
secondary agent, your coding assistant
knows that I can access this library set
but not this library set? How do you
mask that on? And so that's probably one
of my top concerns is around the data
access. Um, right. The second thing is
the non-deterministic nature. As a
security person, I'm always kind of very
linear in thinking of if I put in this
particular, you know, payload, I can
exploit the system and do get it to do
something that I I don't want it to do.
By their very definition, AI and code
generation of AI is non-deterministic.
And so having an audit trail and being
able to meet compliance requirements is
actually really difficult in a world of
AI. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. very interesting
kind of the uh the notion of attacks I
wonder if it's like a new pattern of
attackers in which like uh you know if
it uh if you don't like the weather wait
you know wait five minutes uh type
element is like hey if you're like if
this equal injection didn't work just
try it again in five minutes on it maybe
a new version of AI came along and maybe
that one is vulnerable um yeah and that
manifests itself in different ways
because if you're doing red teaming like
if you're doing sequential prompt
injection you might do the exact same
sequential prompt injection a second
time and it works and the first time it
didn't just simply because of the
nondeterministic nature. So that could
give you an inflated sense of of
confidence and and that that's a problem
in a deterministic security world. Yeah.
Yeah. Absolutely. Because you can't
really attest to to anything having
some some longevity uh to it and how um
I I guess how are people uh dealing sort
of let's sort of focus on those two. I
guess the first one is I think more of a
constraint, right? I I very much relate
to like identity access and uh or you
know instead of me sort of narrowing it
down let's talk a little bit about those
two cases and maybe what are some sort
of mitigating uh controls or what can
someone do except for don't use uh uh
don't use AI right or don't use elements
well I never recommend that I'm a big
believer in embracing it but on the the
authorization authentication mostly
authorization less authentication um so
I we're beginning to see it worked into
some of the underlying frameworks. So
you're beginning to see extensions of
MCP model context protocol to have
authorization in there and in fact we're
a member of the consortium for secure
AI. So you're beginning to see these
frameworks the A to framework is another
one Google announced that at Google next
a month ago or so and at the time didn't
have any authorization in it but already
the working groups are coming together
and saying hey let's introduce it. So my
hope is and Microsoft has embraced that.
So now you have two giants both
embracing the same concept. So my belief
is that in the longer term um we'll
start to work in authorization and
identity and access management into the
systems. Um the it's like I said it's
like uh you wait for the industry
standards to to firm up. You participate
in them if you are uh you know like if
you care and are able to do so. Um I
guess in the meantime you sort of avoid
topics that require them because they're
just not satisfied quite yet.
Yeah, I would be very hesitant to do a
lot around agent to agent communication
or agentic to agentic systems because of
that. Give it six months, give it a year
and I think we're okay. That's not to
say don't embrace AI right now. I just
be more cautious when you get into the
meta layer of of talking.
Yeah. And I think that's okay like
riskreward should always be kind of uh
uh assessed on it. And I guess on the on
the second problem of dynamic code and
the code kind of constantly changing
first of all like I think I think that
probably relies like it's especially
true for agentic systems that might sort
of change the code a bit more uh
dramatically shall we say. So before let
me kind of do a bit of a site tangent.
We come back to this risk like I guess
uh how much do you see agentic uh kind
of full-on you know Devon style of
agentic systems being used uh in
enterprises like are there still in like
a oh this is really cool I want to kind
of try it out in the corner or are you
sort of seeing any sort of um real
adoption on it on enterprise systems?
What I've seen and this is the segment
of the customers maybe that we're
dealing with. What I've seen is uh this
is cool let me try it out on the corner.
I kind of grouped them into three
buckets guy. I have the the highly
agentic autonomous ones like Devon. You
have kind of the medium ones like
augment that, you know, can do a lot of
things, but they're not fully
autonomous. And then you have the more
of the assistant, you know, the the
cursor co-pilot type style. I'd say very
few customers within our customer base
at least are going to the fully agentic.
Um, I would say most of them are
actually in that lower autonomous model
with the co-pilots and cursors and maybe
20ish% 30-ish percent are in kind of the
middle that are doing very much more
augmented uh code assistance. Yeah.
Yeah. Okay. Interesting. So I guess kind
of coming back to the sort of dynamic
nature of it or sort of you know like
how do you deal with compliance I guess
uh you know how do you how do you kind
of pass that uh I guess what what are
there any any kind of innovative uh
approaches that you're sort of seeing
like how are people dealing with that
well a lot of logging in visibility I
said in the early days of the cloud that
had these three problems and the third
one was that there wasn't a lot of
logging in visibility and the good news
is people are logging it and actually
getting interesting metrics out of I I
met with a large financial institution,
a customer of ours that said 11% of our
code is AI generated. And I kind of
scratched my head and I thought, how do
you get to 11%. But what they were doing
was they were logging all the code that
was being submitted into their source
control management systems. And then
they were logging all the code that was
being generated and they were doing some
simple mathematics and division on that.
So, you know, whether that's accurate or
not, for me, the positive outcome is
that they were logging it. They were
actually tracking it. Um and I think
we'll see more of that as as we go
forward. Yeah. Yeah. Makes sense. I
guess maybe let's do some uh some myth
busting you know uh of it. So I guess
which uh which security concern or two
do you feel uh is is you know you can
theorize about it but it's slightly
blown out of proportion.
I tend to think the hallucinations is
pretty blown out of proportion. I'm not
saying it doesn't happen. I just think
that over time we're going to see fewer
hallucinations. And the reason why we'll
see that is mostly because the models
will will test themselves before it
returns output. And so I think um
hallucinations would be one of them.
Identity and access management I think
will get out of that problem over time.
I think data theft is a very low I'm not
saying it's not real. It's definitely
real. But if you ask me to rate it on a
risk uh category, I think the likelihood
of that being exploited is is very low.
And so, you know, I always measure
things on a risk scale as opposed to a
an actual security scale. And so, while
some of these things are real, I just I
think they're lower risk than other
areas, right? Yeah. And they might be
sort of short-term risk. And I guess
which which um when you think about, you
know, fundamentals like you in general
when you think about sort of Genai and
these tools, you know, some flaws are
are just, you know, the baby steps,
right? It's just immature yet. It's
evolving so rapidly. uh and some are
maybe a bit more fundamental. Um I guess
which which security concern or two do
you feel kind of have legs here and
they're going to sort of stay they'll
they'll hurt us for a while or that'll
this be a concern that we really need to
uh uh to to fundamentally sort of
consider because it's going to it's
going to be here. I I would go back to
the same three things that I said about
the cloud and that's because we don't
learn our lessons. In other words, I
think that the configuration of of AI is
is a problem and will be continue to be
a problem generally around the
permissive nature and what data it's
trained on and all of that. The second
thing being over permissive uh identity
access management to the data where
we're giving customers access to let's
say I'm training an LLM and I put all of
my support data in there. Do I really
want to do that if I'm giving customers
access to it because they could break
out of their set of data? So, I think
that's the second one. And then uh the
third one I would go back to the
visibility and logging. I think we're
going to fall into the same trap that we
did before that we're not uh doing
sufficient visibility and logging and we
we end up in the same place we were with
cloud after two or three years. Yeah. Of
not knowing not knowing what is where
and and how is it happening. And I guess
the the the other lens I I I think
sometimes about uh some some security
concerns are uh due to the nature of the
new technology and others are um uh
they're they're just they're just a an
amplification of patterns that we've
already seen before, right? So like
cloud accelerated development or like
DevOps accelerate but like agile came
before that and you know in you know
over time like just sort of things moved
at a faster and faster pace. Um uh and
you know similarly maybe like uh ease of
creation improves and as ease of
creation uh improves like responsible
like the level of scrutiny or maybe the
level of proficiency or uh
professionalism uh involved in watching
these things that goes and that's true
also like when I create images I I
create images in a very non-professional
way and that's okay. I'm not going to
like build any sort of a business around
my kind of AI image creation. I guess do
do you think does that distinction work
for you and and if you had to choose
like which which path you think is
carrier, you know, you're it sounds like
you're sort of maybe leaning more
towards the how we use it versus the
tech. But I don't know if I'm Yeah.
Well, I'm a big believer in that we
should use it. Like I I am not a slow
down at all. We should use AI, embrace
AI. I guess my I always fundamentally go
back to we need to build in security
from the very beginning. the problem
that we've historically fallen into.
Every time we embrace a new
infrastructure, doesn't matter whether
it's cloud or servers or virtualization
or AI, we we forget the fundamentals
which are validate your input, encode
your output, apply identity and access
control management like it's funny while
the threats are or the attacks are
somewhat different because the
infrastructure is different. The root
causes for them guy are it's been the
same for 20 years. I mean ever write
shield we were testing the input that
was going to an application right
yeah yeah a lot of the sort of the same
uh fundamentals I do find for what it's
worth that the I find myself almost more
concern about the explosion of uh of uh
of usage uh than uh than maybe even the
fundamentals of it which are much more
sort of interesting but uh uh we've kind
of seen how security hygiene is the uh
is eventually the things that organiz
ations actually get breached before.
Yeah. What is different today than 20
years ago is there's far more data
behind these systems. So the risk is
greater if compromise occurs. 20 years
ago there wasn't the same amount of data
and now all of the data is behind there
and if the wrong person gets access to
it that can be very detrimental.
Excellent. Uh we have time flies here.
We sort of have five more minutes. I've
got a few more questions to you and then
we have some time for Q&A. So, I just
wanted to remind everybody that you can
post questions in the comments and we'll
have a few minutes for Q&A uh uh in a
few minutes on it. Um I guess uh uh
we're going to try and kind of go
dystopian utopian over here a little
bit. So like we called this talk the age
of risky software. Um let's talk a
little bit about like what is what is
the concern here? What is the uh um you
know the path we need to be beware or or
or is there even one, right? is sort of
a is it set to fall like what what do we
mean by that? the age of risky software
in the early inception days of the new
technology change is always the riskiest
because the pressure on the business and
I'm sure this is true of everyone in the
audience is use AI use AI be more
productive go fast go fast go fast and
so the the early days are are the
greatest risk and we are in the early
days of AI we don't understand it I was
listening to a podcast this weekend of
if you said Dave and busters in a in a
voice message the voice message never
got delivered on an iPhone still true By
the way, today if you Yeah. We don't
understand persona type boards that are
uh uh mysteriously.
Yeah. And we don't understand how the AI
is working sometimes. And so we're in
this age of risky software because we're
in this go fast, go fast, go fast
without truly understanding how it's
working, how to secure it, doing all the
right things. And so we're in the age of
risky software. Yeah. Yeah. I think that
makes sense. I do wonder maybe coming
back to sort of the uh overused sort of
cloud analogy we've been doing here is
when you think about the adoption of the
cloud you know the the initial adoption
was similar like just as you're saying
you know like pressure to adopt uh
people used it and it kind of was sort
of this like world of possibilities and
we kind of went from a place like we
forget this but like infrastructure used
to be a fairly secure thing you know
like people like the servers and all of
that they were sort of run by a fairly
small very professional typically very
security aware
uh group that was moving way too slow,
which is the reason for the drive. And
then cloud kind of opened it up and
suddenly people could do it faster and
more people could do it and oftentimes
without any really understanding of what
it is that they're performing. And you
know fast forward not many years after
uh and until today as you point out like
misconfigurations and sort of flaws uh
in uh in in in sort of infrastructure in
cloud infrastructure typically are such
a massive maybe the top uh cause for uh
for breaches. I guess I wonder as we as
we enable
everyone to be a creator, which I love,
you know, like as a that notion of to be
a developer of sorts of a type of
developer, like a creator of software.
Um, along lines alongside allowing
existing developers to sort of run at
like a much much faster speed, maybe
with a little bit less uh kind of uh
scrutiny on it. uh like our
vulnerabilities in code the the the
equivalent are they going to be sort of
our our Achilles is a heel later and I
don't know like does that resonate is
that a conversation I guess that uh and
and are we doomed to sort of just accept
it if it is because it is what it is
that tech will be adopted I'm an
optimist I believe in the long run it
this will sort itself out but you know
you've titled this the age of risky
software and I think that's why that is
the case like what we're doing is
democratizing coding
uh clearly um and so we're going fast
and we're opening up the aperture
similar to the what the cloud did to
more and more people and so the result
is more code and more code means more
vulnerabilities right now over time I
think we'll start to implement the
controls and the guardrails to to secure
that um and I also don't that's why
you're still going to have developers
just because more people can do
development that doesn't eliminate the
need for developers my son's actually in
computer science and he said dad should
I be worried about you you know, there
there not being a need for developers in
the future. And I say that's ridiculous.
Of course, there's going to need to be
developers. What we're really doing is
opening the aperture to to more
development. And when we do that, what
we need are the security guard rails in
place to ensure that we don't end up in
a similar positioning the cloud ended up
in. Right. Uh uh uh you made a comment
on passing authorization authentication
around when agents uh uh uh uh talk to
agents. That sounds parallel to passing
around ownership and trading value for
intellectual property or microp
payments. Do you see security and
ownership sort of in a similar lens? I
guess this is to me more about like what
what are the sort of the the assets and
the validity of them that are moving
around.
I see the problem as similar but I see
them as very distinct problems. The
ownership of intellectual property and
with AI is a real issue and I don't want
to minimize it. It's true for music.
It's true for art. It's true for code.
It's true for language and books and all
of this. I can I can go tell AI to write
me a book. Well, we should get paid on
that. I I I'm not sure the answer to
that. I think there is a secondary issue
that is similar but a different problem
that has to do with should they get
access to that music, art, you know,
text, code, whatever it happens to be.
So, parallel but distinct. The the
reason why the microp payments is
important is if we want the
proliferation of AI to continue then
there needs to be some model of
attribution because otherwise you're
going to lose all the people that are
contributing data into the LLMs or the
diffusion models that are behind AI.
Yeah. Yeah. No, I think uh I think well
said on it and it's interesting to also
think a little bit about the data assets
that get moved around with um protection
on top of them. So that's also
interesting. In that case maybe they do
blend a little bit more as I almost like
DRM style like you pass along content
with some uh security aspects to it. Um
I guess another question is uh how uh
how will the role of uh attestation play
uh play out in terms of sort of AI
agents and sort of a supply chain like
when we think about creation with AI and
such Jason asked this
you have a view here's one where I
yeah I I actually think the government
we're going to see compliance step in
and usually I'm not a big fan of uh of
regulation of of new technologies
because it's very difficult especially
for startup s deal with it. But I think
because of current compliance
requirements, if you look at PCIDSS or
any of these, you know, regulations or
compliance requirements, they require
validation of certain things. And so
that is going to require attestation of
AI native software that is backed by
LLMs and I think this is going to solve
itself. My only worry and concern guy is
that it becomes very fragmented. What
you don't want is a GDPR for every
country in the world or every state in
the United States. and like that's a bad
position to be in. So hopefully we
consolidate around some very common
wellthoughtout uh requirements or
regulations around stationation. Yeah.
Yeah, that makes sense. But it also
makes sense kind of at the meta level
which is AI will be unpredictable but
there's no reason for it not to be
traceable might not know what will
happen but you want to do that. I think
I've got two more questions. I think we
really kind of have time for one. Uh so
one was about the scope of AI security.
I'm going to pass on that. Uh sorry
about that. It's just I think it's sort
of too big for the time that we have uh
to capture here. I'll ask maybe
something a bit more concrete which is
which security checks uh can developers
currently build into their agents to try
and mitigate as many risks as possible
of ending on a very practical bit of
advice.
Yeah. Well, I would say two things. One
is if you're using open source
components and actually one of the
things that worries me about AI coding
assistants by the way is that it
replaces to some extent open source
components and tries to custom create
them because what's the downstrip
patching and updating of all those open
source components. That's a problem. Um
but I would say two things. One is
validate the packages that you're
pulling in uh for for validation and
then code that you're writing. It's very
easy. You can use AI actually to test
the data flow across that code and to
generate a fix for it. And so if you ask
me very practically, what I think you
should do is validate your open source
packages and if you're writing custom
code, validate that the flow of that
code isn't breaking the build in other
areas. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. I love that.
And uh and I guess, you know, the more
you automate that, the faster you can
run, right? And people kind of forget
that putting guardrails, you know, it
sounds like a a cumbersome thing, but
actually when you put the guardrails in,
when you're sort of running on a bridge
with rails, you can run faster because
you're not afraid to fall. And uh so we
we put those in. Um yeah, time flies.
We're sort of uh here we are sort of uh
35 minutes sort of uh later on. And
Danny, uh huge thanks again for coming
in and sharing this knowledge and for uh
I guess investing in uh in AI security.
Oh, thank you for having me, Guy. It's a
great conversation.